Newton Diehl Baker Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Newton Diehl Baker Papers 1896-1962 1916-1937
MSS11585
Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937
100,000 items
276 containers
110.4 linear feet
31 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
U.S. secretary of war, author, lawyer, and municipal official of Cleveland, Ohio. Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, speeches and articles, newspaper articles, and printed material relating primarily to Baker's post-World War I activities as the head of several business firms and of organizations devoted to education, law and jurisprudence, and philanthropy, relief, and other types of human services.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Clarke, John H. (John Hessin), 1857-1945--Correspondence.; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948--Correspondence.; Davis, Norman H. (Norman Hezekiah), 1878-1944--Correspondence.; Frothingham, Thomas Goddard, 1865-1945--Correspondence.; Hapgood, Norman, 1868-1937--Correspondence.; Hayes, Ralph A.--Correspondence.; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948--Correspondence.; Lape, Esther Everett, 1881-1981--Correspondence.; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974--Correspondence.; Mooney, Charles A., 1879-1931--Correspondence.; Peabody, George Foster, 1852-1938--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Selzer, Louis B.--Correspondence.; Shotwell, James T., 1874-1965--Correspondence.; Ungerleider, Samuel--Correspondence.; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936--Correspondence.; Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1872-1961--Correspondence.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Wright, Howell, 1882-1954--Correspondence.
Organizations
American Institute of Pacific Relations--Correspondence.; American Judicature Society.; Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company.; Cleveland Chamber of Commerce (Cleveland, Ohio); Cleveland Trust Company.; National Consumers' League.; Phi Gamma Delta.; United States. War Department.; Woodrow Wilson Foundation.
Subjects
Banks and banking--Ohio--Cleveland.; Consumers' leagues.; Education--Societies, etc.; Human services.; Justice, Administration of.; Railroads--Management.; Trust companies--Ohio--Cleveland.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.
Places
Cleveland (Ohio)--Commerce.; United States--Politics and government--1913-1921.
Occupations
Authors.; Cabinet officers.; Lawyers.; Public officials--Ohio.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Newton Diehl Baker, U.S. secretary of war, author, lawyer, and municipal official of Cleveland, Ohio, were given to the Library of Congress by Baker's children, Elizabeth Baker McGean, Newton D. Baker III, and Margaret Baker Wright in 1952. Major additions were made by Ralph Hayes in 1956 and the Cleveland Municipal Reference Library, Cleveland, Ohio, in 1966; other material was added through multiple gifts, 1939-1993.
Related Material
Related collections in the Manuscript Division include a microfilm edition of Newton Diehl Baker Letterbooks consisting of letters written or signed by Baker during his terms as city solicitor (1903-1912) and mayor (1912-1915) of Cleveland, Ohio, held in the original by the Cleveland Municipal Reference Library.
Access and Restrictions
The Newton Baker Papers of are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of part of these papers is available on thirty-one reels. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition as available.
Biographical Note
1871, Dec. 3 Born, Martinsburg, W.Va.
1892 B.A., Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md.
1894 L.L.B. Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Va.
1902 Married Elizabeth Leopold
1896 1897 Private secretary to Postmaster General William L. Wilson
1897 1899 Private law practice, Martinsburg, W.Va.
1899 Private law practice, Cleveland, Ohio
1901 1902 First assistant city solicitor, Cleveland, Ohio
1902 1912 City solicitor, Cleveland, Ohio
1912 1916 Mayor, Cleveland, Ohio
1916 1921 Secretary of war
1918 Published Frontiers of Freedom. New York: George H. Doran Co.
1921 Private law practice, firm of Baker, Hostetler, and Sidlo, Cleveland, Ohio
1925 Published Progress and the Constitution. New York: Scribner's Sons
1928 Appointed to permanent Court of Arbitration at the Hague, Netherlands
1929 Appointed to Law Enforcement Commission
1932 Published Bolshevism, Fascism and Capitalism. New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Press
1936 Published Why We Went to War. Freeport, N.Y.: Harper & Brother for the Council on Foreign Relations
1937, 25 Dec. Died, Shaker Heights, Ohio
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Newton Diehl Baker (1871-1937) span the years 1896-1962, with the bulk concentrated in the period 1916-1937. The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, speeches and articles, newspaper articles, and printed material relating primarily to Baker's post-World War I activities as the head of several business firms and of organizations devoted to education, law and jurisprudence, and philanthropy, relief, and other types of human services. The firms and organizations include the American Judicature Society, Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, Cleveland Chamber of Commerce, Cleveland Trust Company, National Consumer's League, Phi Gamma Delta, and Woodrow Wilson Foundation. Included is material relating to Baker's post as secretary of war in Woodrow Wilson's cabinet during World War I.
Correspondents include the American Institute of Pacific Relations, John H. Clarke, Josephus Daniels, Norman H. Davis, Thomas Goddard Frothingham, Norman Hapgood, Ralph A. Hayes, Thomas W. Lamont, Esther Everett Lape, Walter Lippmann, Charles A. Mooney, George Foster Peabody, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Louis B. Selzer, James Thomson Shotwell, Samuel Ungerleider, George W. Wickersham, Edith Bolling Galt Wilson, and Howell Wright.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Correspondence and Other Papers, 1916-1922
General Correspondence, 1922-1937
Speeches and Writings, 1915-1937
Miscellany, 1918-1935
Ralph Hayes File, 1916-1962
Letterbooks, 1896-1917
Addition, 1917-1930
Container List
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1916-1922 (Box 1-15, Reel 1-13)
  Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 17,577
  - Personal Correspondence, 1916-1922 (Box 1-13, Reel 1-12)
    Letters sent and received.
    Arranged chronologically by year and therein alphabetically.
    - 1916 (Box 1, Reel 1)
      - "A-W" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
      - Wilson, Woodrow
    - 1917
      - "A-F" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
      - "G-L" miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 2, Reel 1-2)
      - "M-V" miscellaneous, (10 folders) (Box 3, Reel 2)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, (10 folders) (Box 4, Reel 3)
      - "W" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 3-4)
      - Yeates, Charles E., report on the Philippines, 1917
    - 1918
      - "A-F"miscellaneous, (8 folders)
      - "G-L" miscellaneous, (11 folders) (Box 6, Reel 4-5)
      - "M-V" miscellaneous, (10 folders) (Box 7, Reel 5)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, (9 folders) (Box 8, Reel 5-6)
      - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - 1919 (Box 9, Reel 6-7)
      - "A-G" miscellaneous, (9 folders)
      - "H-P" miscellaneous, (12 folders) (Box 10, Reel 7-8)
      - "R-V" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 11, Reel 8-9)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, (2 folders)
      - "W" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - 1920
      - "A-C" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - "D-P" miscellaneous, (13 folders) (Box 12, Reel 9-10)
        - "Q-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders) (Box 13, Reel 10-11)
    - 1921
      - "A-F" miscellaneous, (6 folders)
        - "G-Z" miscellaneous, (13 folders) (Box 13(a), Reel 11-12)
    - 1922, "A-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1916-1921 (Box 14, Reel 12-13)
    Arranged chronologically by year.
    - 1916-1921, (9 folders) (Box 14, Reel 12-13)
  - Subject File, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Reel 13)
    Letters sent and received and minutes and reports relating to the Supreme War Council and to shipping during World War I.
    Arranged by topic.
    - Supreme War Council, minutes of meetings, 1917-1918, (9 folders) (Box 15, Reel 13)
    - "Shipping AEF," war transport, 1917, (2 folders)
- General Correspondence, 1922-1937 (Box 16-243)
  Letters and memoranda sent and received with attached and related reports, printed matter, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization.
  - "Aa-Al" miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 17)
  - Academy of Political Science, speech, 1934
  - Adult Education Association
    - 1927-1928
    - 1933-1937 (Box 18)
  - "Am-Ar" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 19)
  - American Arbitration Association, 1927-1932 (Box 20)
  - American Association for Adult Education, 1929-1936
  - American Bar Association
    - 1932-1933
    - 1934-1935 (Box 21)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 22)
    - 1937 (Box 23)
    - Audit report, 1936-1937
    - Booklets, statements, etc., 1937
    - Board of Governors, 1936-1937 (Box 24)
    - Committee on Jurisprudence and Law Reform, 1937 (Box 25)
    - Committee on Portraits, 1935
    - Committee on Radio, Press, and Bar, 1936-1937
    - Committees of state and local bar associations, 1936-1937
    - Coordination Committee, 1935
    - Executive Committee, 1936 (Box 26)
    - House of Delegates, 1937
    - Memoranda, comments, clippings, etc., 1936
  - American-British Friendly Relations Society, 1935
  - American Foreign Bondholders' Protective Committee, 1933
  - American Foundation Committee of the American Peace Awardn
    - 1931-1932
    - 1933-1934 (Box 27)
  - American Foundation for the Blind, 1934
  - American Iron and Steel Institute, speech, 1937
  - American Judicature Society
    - 1930-1936
    - 1937 (Box 28)
  - American Law Institute
    - 1931-1937
    - Advisory Committee on Criminal Justice, 1934
  - American Legion Convention, 1931 (Box 29)
  - American Legion Convention Corporation, speech, 1936
  - American Philosophical Society, 1936
  - American Red Cross, 1932-1937
  - American Shakespeare Foundation, 1927-1929 (Box 30)
  - American Social Hygiene Association
    - 1929-1937
    - Report by the Special Body of Experts
  - American Youth Commission, 1936-1937 (Box 31)
  - Applications for positions, 1931-1937 (Box 32)
  - Armistice Day, American Legion, 1930
  - Armistice Day, speech, 1932
  - "As-Az"
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 33)
  - Atlantic Monthly, article, 1934
  - Atkinson, Will, 1927
  - Ayres, Leonard P., 1922-1925, 1936
  - "Baa-Bar" miscellaneous (Box 34)
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1936 (Box 35)
    - 1937 (Box 36)
  - Baker, Frank H.
    - 1922-1936
    - 1937 (Box 37)
  - Baker, Julian C., 1922-1937
  - Baker, Newton Diehl
    - Birthday greetings, 1936-1937
    - Personal, 1937
  - Baker, Newton D., III, 1932
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Co.
    - 1922-1923
    - 1925-1931 (Box 38)
    - 1932-1937 (Box 39)
  - "Bas-Bd" miscellaneous
    - 1923-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 40)
  - "Be-Bh"miscellaneous
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1936 (Box 41)
    - 1937 (Box 42)
  - "Bi-Bn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 43)
  - Biskind, Elliot, 1930-1931
  - Bliss, E. Goring
    - 1930
    - 1934 (Box 44)
  - Bliss, Tasker Howard, 1929-1930
  - Block, Elizabeth D., 1933-1936
  - "Bo-Bq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 45)
  - Boston, Mass., speech, 1931-1932
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1934-1937
  - "Bra-Brn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1937 (Box 46)
  - Brett, Zillah Quayle, 1935 (Box 47)
  - "Bro-Bt" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 48)
  - Brooklyn, N.Y., speech, 1932
    - 1922-1929
    - 1930-1935 (Box 49)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 50)
  - "Ca-Cd" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 51)
  - Callahan, P. H., 1926-1937 (Box 52)
  - Carnegie Corp.
    - 1931-1932
    - 1933-1935 (Box 53)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 54)
  - "Ce-Cn" miscellaneous
    - 1922
    - 1923-1930 (Box 55)
    - 1931-1934 (Box 56)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 57)
  - Century Association, 1932-1937
  - Chambers, D. L., 1933
  - Chestnut, W. Calvin, 1922-1937 (Box 58)
  - Child Guidance Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, 1932
  - Church Peace Union, 1931
  - Cincinnati, Ohio, speech, 1932
  - Citizen's League of Cleveland, Cleveland, Ohio, 1936
  - Clarke, John H. (Box 59)
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 60)
  - Clayton v. Crowell, 1924
  - Cleveland American Legion Foundation, Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1932
  - Cleveland Association for Adult Education, Cleveland, Ohio, 1929-1932
  - Cleveland Association for Criminal Justice, Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1922-1924
    - 1925-1934 (Box 61)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 62)
    - Committee on Parole, 1927
    - "A Study of Criminal Court Bail Bonds in Cleveland, Ohio," 1936
  - Cleveland Bar Association, Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1923-1924
    - 1925-1933 (Box 63)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 64)
    - Speech, 1933
  - Cleveland Baseball Co., Cleveland, Ohio, 1932-1934
  - Cleveland Chamber of Commerce, Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1922-1926
    - 1927-1937 (Box 65)
  - Cleveland Community Fund, Cleveland, Ohio, 1929
  - Cleveland College, Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio See also Containers 231-233, Western Reserve University
    - 1927-1928
    - 1927-1933 (Box 66)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 67)
    - 1937 (Box 68)
    - Guarantor Solicitation, 1927
  - Cleveland Community Fund, Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1930-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 69)
  - Cleveland Conference for Educational Cooperation, Cleveland, Ohio, 1928-1932
  - Cleveland Grays, Cleveland, Ohio, 1937 (Box 70)
  - Cleveland Humane Society, Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1933
  - Cleveland Orchestra, Cleveland, Ohio, 1928-1937
  - Cleveland Packard Co., Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1937 (Box 71)
  - Cleveland Port Advisory Board, Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1932
  - Cleveland Public Works Committee, Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1932
  - Cleveland Safety Council, Cleveland, Ohio, 1932
  - Cleveland Trust Co., Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1928-1935
    - 1936-1937 (Box 72)
    - In the matter of A. F. Holden's Trust, 1930
  - Cleveland World Court Committee, Cleveland, Ohio
  - Clothing Arbitration, 1935
  - "Coa-Con" miscellaneous (Box 73)
    - 1924-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 74)
  - Colcord, Samuel George Gordon Battle, 1930-1932
  - Colletti investigation, 1931
  - Collver-Miller Co.
    - 1933-1936
    - 1937 (Box 75)
  - Columbia University Law School Alumni Association, New York, N.Y., speech, 1932
  - Commission on Care and Education of American Youth, 1935
  - Committee for the Nation
    - 1932-1933
    - 1934-1936 (Box 76)
  - Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students, 1929-1930
  - Connor, W. D., 1929-1931
  - Consolidated Reporting Co., Conference of Trustees of Colleges and Universities, 1935
  - Constitution Day, speech, 1932
  - "Coo-Cq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1924
    - 1925-1935 (Box 77)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 78)
  - Cook Lectures, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1930
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1926-1937
  - Country Club, Chagrin Falls, Ohio 1933 (Box 79)
  - County Emergency Committee, Cuyahoga County, Ohio, 1931-1932
  - Cox, James M., 1930-1933
  - "Cr-Ct" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 80)
  - Credit Extension Union
    - 1928-1934
    - 1935 (Box 81)
  - Crile Clinic Committee, Cleveland, Ohio, 1929
  - "Da-Dh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1931 (Box 82)
    - 1932-1935 (Box 83)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 84)
  - Dalton, H. G., 1933-1937
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1926-1937
  - Davey, Martin L., 1932
  - Davis, John W., 1929-1936
  - Davis, Norman H., 1930
  - Deane Plan, 1933
  - Delta Theta Phi Fraternity
    - 1929-1936
    - 1937 (Box 85)
  - Democratic party committees, 1928-1936
  - Democratic Party County Executive Committee, Cuyahoga County, Ohio, 1922-1924
  - Democratic party (local), 1922 (Box 86)
  - Democratic party, Ohio
  - "Di-Dq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 87)
  - Disarmament, 1931
  - Distinguished Service Medal
  - Douglas, Wolman, regarding Baker letter, 2 June 1936
  - "Dr-Dz" miscellaneous (Box 88)
    - 1922-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 89)
  - Durbin, James, 1927-1929
  - "Ea-En" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1929
    - 1930-1935 (Box 90)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 91)
  - Education Extension Council, Cleveland, Ohio, 1925-1926
  - Ellis, Lynn W., 1933
  - "Eo-Ez" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 92)
  - Episcopal High School, Alexandria, Va., 1933-1937
  - "Fa-Fk" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1926
    - 1927-1932 (Box 93)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 94)
  - Federal Home Loan Banking System, civic committee, Cleveland, Ohio, 1932 (Box 95)
  - Federated churches, Cleveland, Ohio, speech, 1932
  - Fels, Mary, 1929-1936
  - Fesler, Mayo, 1929-1935
  - Filene, E. A., 1929-1936
  - "Fl-Fq" miscellaneous
    - 1922
    - 1923-1935 (Box 96)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 97)
  - Foch, Marshal Ferdinand, Memorial Committee of New York and New Jersey, 1930
  - Foreign Affairs
    - 1931-1937
    - "Why We Went to War," 1936
  - Foreign Affairs Council
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1937 (Box 98)
  - Foreign Affairs Institute, 1933
  - Foreign Bondholders Protective Council
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1937 (Box 99)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1929-1937
  - Fosdick, Raymond B.
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1937 (Box 100)
  - "Fr-Fz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 101)
  - Frothingham, Thomas G.
    - 1925
    - Book, 1927
    - 1928
  - "Ga-Gh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1926
    - 1927-1937 (Box 102)
  - Gas formula, 1935
  - "Gi-Gq" miscellaneous
    - 1922
    - 1923-1931 (Box 103)
    - 1932-1937 (Box 104)
  - Glass, Carter, 1929
  - Gongwer, W. B.
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1936 (Box 105)
  - Good Housekeeping Magazine, 1930-1931
  - Goodrich Social Settlement, 1926-1934
  - Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co. (Box 106)
    - 1935-1937
    - Board of Directors, 1934
  - "Gr-Gz" miscellaneous (Box 107)
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1937 (Box 108)
  - Griswold, B. Howell, 1929-1933 (Box 109)
  - "Haa-Haq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 110)
  - Hall of Fame, New York University, New York, N.Y.
    - 1930-1935
    - 1936 (Box 111)
  - Hapgood, Norman, 1932
  - "Har-Hd" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1936 (Box 112)
    - 1937
  - Harbord, James G., 1929-1936 (Box 113)
  - Harper, J. C., 1929-1933
  - Havens, Munson, 1926-1934
  - Hayden, Joel B., 1925-1929
  - Hayes, Ralph
    - 1922
    - 1923-1927 (Box 114)
    - 1928-1931 (Box 115)
    - 1932 (Box 116)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 117)
  - "He-Hh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1926
    - 1927-1937 (Box 118)
  - "Hi-Hn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1937 (Box 119)
  - "Ho-Ht" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1930 (Box 120)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 121)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 122)
  - House and Senate bills, 1930-1932
  - Howard, Roy Wilson, 1932-1934
  - Howells, Thomas J., 1924
  - Howie, John McF., 1930
  - "Hu-Hz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1933 (Box 123)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 124)
  - Hudson, Manley O., 1929, 1935-1937
  - "I" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1935
    - 1936-1937 (Box 125)
  - Illinois v. Lucas, 1931
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
    - 1928-1932
    - 1932-1934 (Box 126)
    - 1934-1936 (Box 127)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 128)
    - American Council
      - 1929-1930
      - 1931 (Box 129)
  - Institute of Politics, Williamstown, Mass., 1931
  - Institute of Public Administration & Public Administration Clearing House, 1932-1933
  - Investigation of Army Air Corps, 1934 (Box 130)
  - International Chamber of Commerce, 1929-1931
  - Italian decoration, 1931
  - "J" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1934 (Box 131)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 132)
  - Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Association
  - Joffre, Marshal, Monument Committee, 1937
  - John, Henry J., 1930-1934
  - Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md. (Box 133)
    - 1923-1929
    - 1930-1936 (Box 134)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 135)
    - Presidential search
      - 1928-1929
      - 1934-1935
  - Judge Advocate General's Office, 1922-1925 (Box 136)
  - Judicial Council of Ohio, 1930-1932
  - Juvenile Court, Harry L. Eastman, 1930-1931
  - "Ka-Kh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1924
    - 1925-1932 (Box 137)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 138)
  - Kates, Philip, 1932
  - Keppel, Frederic P., 1929-1932
  - "Ki-Kq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1926
    - 1927-1937 (Box 139)
  - "Kr-Kz", 1922-1937 (Box 140)
  - "La-Ld" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1932 (Box 141)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 142)
  - Labor, 1922-1923
  - Lamont, Thomas W., 1936-1937
  - Lape, Esther Everett
    - 1927
    - 1928-1930 (Box 143)
  - "Le-Lh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 144)
  - League for the Organization of Progress, 1930
  - League of Nations, 1923-1935
  - League of Nations Association
    - 1929-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 145)
  - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association
    - 1922-1926
    - 1922-1928 (Box 146)
  - League of Nations, statement, 1932
  - Leopold, Howard, estate of, 1931
  - "Li-Lz" miscellaneous
    - 1922
    - 1923-1932 (Box 147)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 148)
  - Lippmann, Walter
    - 1929-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 149)
  - "Ma-Mb" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1936
    - 1927-1931 (Box 150)
    - 1932-1935 (Box 151)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 152)
  - "Mc" miscellaneous, 1922-1928
  - "McA-McD" miscellaneous
    - 1929-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 153)
  - McDonald, James G., 1926-1928
  - "McE-McK" miscellaneous
    - 1929-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 154)
  - McGean, John P. and Betty Baker, 1926-1927
  - McGuire, Murray M., 1926
  - "McL-Md" miscellaneous, 1929-1937
  - March, Peyton
    - 1931
    - 1932-1936 (Box 155)
  - Mather, Samuel, 1929-1931
  - Matson, Carlton, 1926
  - "Me-Mn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1933 (Box 156)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 157)
  - Military justice
  - Miller, Ray T., 1932
  - "Mo-Mx" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1924
    - 1925-1931 (Box 158)
    - 1932-1937 (Box 159)
  - Mirian Kerruish Stage Memorial, 1933, 1937
  - Mooney, Charles A.
    - 1929
    - 1930 (Box 160)
  - Municipal Light Plant, Cleveland, Ohio, 1924
  - Muscle Shoals, Tenn., 1924
  - Mutual Life Insurance Co. of New York, 1931-1937
  - "My-Mz" miscellaneous
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929-1937 (Box 161)
  - "Na-Nn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1935 (Box 162)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 163)
  - National Advisory Council on Radio in Education, 1931-1937
  - National Aeronautic Association, 1923 (Box 164)
  - National Broadcasting Co.
    - 1933-1937
    - 1931-1936 (Box 165)
  - National Citizens Committee for the Welfare & Relief Mobilization
    - 1932
    - 1933 (Box 166)
  - National Citizens' Council Board, 1936
  - National Commission on Law Observance & Enforcement (Box 167)
    - 1928-1931
    - 1931 (Box 168)
  - National Committee on Calendar Simplification, 1931
  - National Conference of Jews and Christians
    - 1929-1932
    - 1932-1935 (Box 169)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 170)
    - Williamstown Institute of Human Relations, Williams College, Williamstown, Mass., 1935
  - National Consumers League
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 171)
  - National Crime Commission
    - 1925-1926
    - 1926-1928 (Box 172)
    - 1929-1932 (Box 173)
  - National Economy League, 1932-1935
  - National Educational Survey Voluntary Appointing Committee, 1930-1932
  - National Institute of Public Administration
    - 1929
    - 1930-1931 (Box 174)
  - National Peace Conference